This video is for you to introduce CloFab
CloFab function can make it easy for you to create high-quality digital fabrics
And apply it to 3D clothing immediately to check the effect
Before that, you must use a seamless fabric generator to create a pattern
And fabric generator to create physical properties
Starting from 2025.1 version
You can use these two functions seamlessly in CloFab
In addition, using the CloZFab fabric measurement kit
This is a new solution based on Clo's latest AI technology
You can more accurately and faster digitalize the fabric
CloZFab fabric measurement kit is a product for face-to-face corporate customer sales
We will provide a detailed user manual when it is released
Please pay attention
Now let's see how to use it
There are three ways to open CloFab
First, if you want to start creating new fabrics from the beginning
You can click on the CloFab icon at the top of the window fabric selection card
Activate CloFab window to create new fabrics
Second, if you want to modify existing fabrics
You can click on the icon on the right side of the fabric project in the object window
Then select from the list that appears
The physical property or the physical property to start it
Finally, you can also start it from the main menu at the top
Click on the fabric menu
Then click on the CloFab flag menu
You can start creating new fabrics
In order to check the results directly on 3D clothing
Use Ctrl plus A to select all the versions and apply the new added fabrics
The new fabric is currently the default fabric
You can simulate the synchronization first
First, at the top of the window
Enter the name of the fabric
If necessary, you can also enter the supplier and all the information
At the top is the preview area
Currently providing user manuals and related information about ZFabKit
In the middle, you can see it is mainly divided into
Physical property and physical property selection cards
The basic work process is to create a physical property first, then start the project
Then set the physical property
But if you already have a sticker
You can directly enter the physical property selection card and only generate the physical property
You can also see the relevant introduction and link at the top
Let's start with the physical property selection card
At the bottom of the physical property selection card
You can choose how to create a physical sticker
If you have CloZFab scanning device
You can use the first option
And open the picture
Is based on the image file you already have to create a fabric sticker
Even if you don't have a scanning device, you can use it
I will click it to import the file
At this time, if you follow the specified file naming rules
You can automatically add a PBR sticker to the same file
When opening the picture, it will first display the cut
Convenient for you to cut the unnecessary area on the fabric
You can drag the screen to the center of the cut frame
Four corners or the handle on the side
Actual adjustment of the cut area
To move the position of the cut area
Just click and drag
If you want to redo the cut area
Please click the redo button in the upper right corner
After adjusting the cut area to the required part to keep the fabric
Click the selection icon in the upper right corner
Or press the return button on the keyboard to complete the cut
After the cut is completed, you will enter the seamless processing step
You need to find the repeat area in the fabric text
Select the automatic option in the selection screen menu
And select the pattern type of the fabric
System will be displayed in the top right corner of the screen
You can automatically analyze the best effect in the designated area
You can choose two pattern types
The repeat type is used for evenly repeating patterns
For example, the grid pattern
The single color irregular type is used for
No specific pattern or pattern irregular distribution fabric
Please note that this type is based on the information of the line drawing
Therefore, there must be a line drawing to get the correct result
For this fabric
I will choose the repeat type and drag to define the repeat area
The automatic analysis part will be displayed as a grid
You can preview the repeat results based on the area
When selecting an area with four pattern repetitions
The automatic evaluation effect is the most accurate and most efficient
You can view the seamless effect on the top
Open the grid display to check the repeat unit
Click the switch menu icon on the left side
You can also check the status of each picture
You can also select the repeat area calculation at the bottom again
If the brightness of the result is not uniform
You can use the average function in the adjustment panel
Enter the number or adjust the slider to correct
Next, let's see how to manually set the repeat area
To switch to manual mode
You can directly cancel the selection of automatic options in the setting panel
Or click the button in the lower right corner of the selected area to switch
After entering manual mode
You can directly adjust the selected area
You can adjust the corners and edges by
Using the handle to adjust the selected area
Of course, you can also refresh the selection and then adjust
Now I will align the four points of the selected area to the same position
After you are satisfied with the selection
Click the hook button to confirm
The upper preview window will appear
The result of the manually selected area
Click the application
You can check the 3D clothing texture effect
Next, click on the physical property option card
To create a physical property
At the top, there is a button on the Clozefab fabric test device
It is a switch menu
If you have a Clozefab fabric test device
You can use it at any time
Even if you don't have one
You can easily create the right fabric for your clothing
All you need to do is enter the material and weight of the fabric type
First, select the fabric type
The component items that can be used will change according to the fabric type
So please click on the sequence to choose
Next, enter the component information
First, select the fiber type and enter the content percentage of each item
Then enter the weight and thickness of the fabric
In the preview of the top
You can see the actual 3D scroll effect based on the information you entered
The texture sticker we created before will also be reflected in this preview
There will also be three pre-set texture pictures of the fabric type below
Click to switch to use
Click again to switch back to the original texture
Click the application below
The physical property can be applied to 3D clothing
Open the simulation to check the body effect
Through the model type of pull-down menu in the upper left corner of the window
You can check the versatility of the fabric under other conditions
You can control the visual image in the preview window like in the 3D window
And you can lock the self-defined visual image by clicking the lock icon
Click the arrow next to the detailed information
You will be able to directly edit the physical properties generated
But please remember that manually changing these values ​​means
You will change the result based on the original fabric information creation
In other words, the physical properties will no longer correspond to the input data
Therefore, be sure to be careful when adjusting
After the fabric creation is complete
You can use the bottom button to apply or save your work
If you want to save the fabric as a ZFAB file
Please click the save button in the lower left corner
In the preview image menu, you can choose
Which type of image to use as the preview of the fabric in the warehouse
In the default situation, the application of the fabric sticker image
But you can also add a self-defined image according to your needs
Select through the save function
You can choose which stickers and fabric files to be saved together
You can only choose and save the PBR sticker that can be used
Choose the sticker to be saved
After saving the sticker
Click to confirm that the file resource manager window will appear
The fabric will be saved with the name you defined in CloFab
If it contains a sticker
It will automatically generate other file names
It's just a type of each sticker
Finally, if you click the new button
The content in each option card will be reset to the initial state
Now let's take a look through the library
The previously saved fabric and its PBR sticker
I hope you can use the new CloFab
Create more efficient and high-quality digital fabrics
Thank you for watching